=His Chosen Favor=
=مفضلته المختارة=
(I'm burning with fever, you're burning with desire)
(أنا أحترق من الحمى، وأنتِ تحترقين من الرغبة)
=Episode 14=
=الحلقة 14=
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
refuse to kneel?
يرفضون الركوع؟
Guards! Make her kneel.
أيها الحراس! اجعلوها تركع.
- Yes.
- نعم.
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
- What are you doing? - Let me go!
- ماذا تفعل؟ - دعني أذهب!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
- Greetings, Your Majesty.
- تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
Your Majesty, Lu Zhen'er has shown me disrespect.
جلالتك، لقد أظهرت لي لو تشن إير عدم احترام.
That's why
لهذا السبب
I ordered someone to lecture her.
أمرت شخصاً ما أن يلقي عليها محاضرة.
Disrespect must be punished.
يجب معاقبة عدم الاحترام.
Your Majesty, you have no idea
يا جلالة الملك، ليس لديك أدنى فكرة
how arrogantly she treated me moments ago.
كم كانت تعاملني بغطرسة قبل لحظات.
She mocked me, saying I'd end up like her.
سخرت مني قائلةً إنني سأنتهي مثلها.
When I demanded an apology,
عندما طالبت بالاعتذار،
she completely ignored my order.
لقد تجاهلت طلبي تماماً.
Your Majesty, I'm a Noble Consort.
جلالتك، أنا قرينة نبيلة.
How dare she treat me like this?
كيف تجرؤ على معاملتي بهذه الطريقة؟
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
did you really treat her that way?
هل عاملتها حقاً بهذه الطريقة؟
I've done nothing wrong.
لم أفعل أي خطأ.
Why should I kneel?
لماذا يجب أن أركع؟
Does your innocence matter?
هل لبراءتك أهمية؟
You're a slave.
أنت عبد.
She is your master.
هي سيدتك.
You obey whatever she commands.
عليك أن تطيع كل ما تأمر به.
You have no right to judge.
ليس لك الحق في الحكم.
You know who's boss here, right?
أنت تعرف من هو الرئيس هنا، أليس كذلك؟
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
apologize to Noble Consort now!
أعتذر الآن للقرينة النبيلة!
Yes.
نعم.
I acknowledge my fault.
أقر بخطئي.
Punish me, Your Highness.
عاقبني يا صاحب السمو.
Forget it. I won't stoop to your level.
انسَ الأمر. لن أنزل إلى مستواك.
(Xiao Wenjing,)
(شياو ون جينغ،)
(are you sure we should torment each other?)
(هل أنت متأكد من أننا يجب أن نعذب بعضنا البعض؟)
(So hungry.)
(أشعر بجوع شديد.)
(Since Xiao Wenjing issued that decree,)
(منذ أن أصدر شياو وينجينغ ذلك المرسوم،)
(the Laundry Service stopped feeding me.)
(توقفت خدمة غسيل الملابس عن إطعامي.)
Who did this?
من فعل هذا؟
You?
أنت؟
Don't disturb my sleep.
لا تزعج نومي.
Are you insane?
هل أنت مجنون؟
Did you pour water on my blanket?
هل سكبت الماء على بطانيتي؟
What blanket?
أي بطانية؟
I know nothing.
لا أعرف شيئاً.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Throwing your weight around in the Laundry Service?
هل تستغل نفوذك في مجال خدمات غسيل الملابس؟
Still imagine yourself as Consort Lu?
هل ما زلت تتخيل نفسك في دور القرينة لو؟
His Majesty decreed long ago
أصدر جلالته مرسوماً منذ زمن بعيد
that everyone in the palace,
أن كل شخص في القصر،
whether maid or eunuch,
سواء كانت خادمة أو خصي،
may order you about.
قد يصدر لك أوامر بشأن ذلك.
If you dare disobey,
إذا تجرأت على العصيان،
we'll report you to His Majesty
سنبلغ جلالته عنك
and he'll punish you.
وسوف يعاقبك.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Won't let me sleep?
لن يدعني أنام؟
Then none of you will sleep.
إذن لن ينام أحد منكم.
His Majesty may punish me,
قد يعاقبني جلالته.
but if any of you bully me,
لكن إذا قام أي منكم بالتنمر عليّ،
I'll fight you to the death.
سأقاتلك حتى الموت.
I always repay grievances
أنا دائماً أرد الجميل.
and settle scores.
وتصفية الحسابات.
Why the big attitude?
لماذا هذا التكبر؟
His Majesty abandoned you anyway.
لقد تخلى عنك جلالته على أي حال.
Exactly!
بالضبط!
Why the big attitude?
لماذا هذا التكبر؟
(Xiao Wenjing,)
(شياو ون جينغ،)
(you are so mean!)
(أنت لئيم جداً!)
(You're actually serious about this.)
(أنت جاد فعلاً بشأن هذا الأمر.)
Lu Zhen'er, get up now!
لو تشن إير، انهضي الآن!
No slacking allowed!
ممنوع التراخي!
Lu Zhen'er! Up!
لو زينير! أعلى!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
What's wrong with disciplining a lazy maid?
ما الخطأ في تأديب خادمة كسولة؟
She's no longer a consort!
لم تعد محظية!
Quit acting like a consort here.
توقف عن التصرف كزوجة هنا.
Showing mercy costs nothing.
إظهار الرحمة لا يكلف شيئاً.
She might
ربما
regain imperial favor someday.
ستستعيد حظوتها الإمبراطورية يوماً ما.
Your Highness, are you alright?
صاحب السمو، هل أنت بخير؟
You're burning up!
أنت تحترق!
Your Highness, wait here.
يا صاحب السمو، انتظر هنا.
I'll fetch the imperial physician.
سأحضر الطبيب الإمبراطوري.
Eunuch Fu, please wait.
أيها الخصي فو، من فضلك انتظر.
Miss Yindan,
من الآنسة يين،
where are you rushing to?
إلى أين أنت مسرع؟
Consort Lu has fallen ill.
أصيبت الزوجة لو بالمرض.
The imperial physicians won't treat her,
الأطباء الإمبراطوريون يرفضون علاجها.
claiming it's His Majesty's orders.
ويزعمون أنها أوامر جلالته.
Please plead with His Majesty.
أرجوكم توسلوا إلى جلالته.
Consort Lu is ill?
هل المحظية لو مريضة؟
I'll report to His Majesty at once.
سأقدم تقريراً إلى جلالته على الفور.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Stop!
قف!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Consort Lu is ill.
كونسورت لو مريضة.
I'll report to Your Majesty.
سأقدم تقريري إلى جلالتكم.
Consort Lu is ill?
هل المحظية لو مريضة؟
She was full of vitality days ago.
كانت مفعمة بالحيوية قبل أيام.
How could she fall ill suddenly?
كيف يمكن أن تمرض فجأة؟
Could it be she's faking illness
هل من الممكن أنها تتظاهر بالمرض؟
just to skip work?
هل الهدف هو التغيب عن العمل فقط؟
Her Highness would never do that.
صاحبة السمو لن تفعل ذلك أبداً.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
What do you think you are?
ماذا تظن نفسك؟
How dare you speak to me like that!
كيف تجرؤ على التحدث معي بهذه الطريقة!
You ill-mannered wretch!
يا لك من وغد سيء الأخلاق!
Kneel here right now!
اركع هنا الآن!
You'll rise only
لن تنهض إلا
when I permit it.
عندما أسمح بذلك.
Without my order,
بدون طلبي،
don't enter or disturb His Majesty and me.
لا تدخلوا ولا تزعجوا جلالته ولا أنا.
Don't worry, Miss Yindan.
لا تقلقي يا آنسة يندان.
His Majesty may come out shortly.
قد يخرج جلالته قريباً.
What's that outside?
ما هذا الشيء الموجود بالخارج؟
Just a nobody. I've dismissed her.
مجرد شخص عادي. لقد صرفتها عن العمل.
Be quiet.
كن هادئاً.
Don't laugh.
لا تضحك.
Yes.
نعم.
Eunuch Fu, Consort Lu is gravely ill.
الخصي فو، المحظية لو مريضة مرضاً خطيراً.
No more delays.
لا مزيد من التأخير.
Don't panic.
لا تُصب بالذعر.
I'll fetch the physician.
سأحضر الطبيب.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
thank you today.
شكراً لكم اليوم.
No thanks needed between us.
لا حاجة للشكر بيننا.
Here.
هنا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
No thanks between us.
لا شكر على واجب بيننا.
If you thank me again,
إذا شكرتني مرة أخرى،
I will be angry.
سأغضب.
Zhen'er,
زينير،
His Majesty is harsh to you.
جلالته قاسٍ عليكم.
Still wish to stay in the palace?
هل ما زلت ترغب في البقاء في القصر؟
Do I have any other choices?
هل لدي أي خيارات أخرى؟
If you want,
إذا أردت،
I can take you out of the palace.
أستطيع أن أخرجك من القصر.
How?
كيف؟
I'll devise a way.
سأجد طريقة.
I only ask if you want to.
أنا أسأل فقط إذا كنت ترغب في ذلك.
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحية طيبة، صاحب السمو.
Zhen'er is seriously ill.
تشن إر مريضة بشدة.
His Majesty just summoned a physician.
استدعى جلالته طبيباً للتو.
How utterly heartless!
يا له من قسوة قلب!
Fu An, who sent you here,
فو آن، من أرسلك إلى هنا؟
Yindan or His Majesty?
يندان أم جلالته؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
His Majesty
صاحب الجلالة
is occupied.
مشغول.
So it wasn't His Majesty.
إذن لم يكن جلالته.
Zhen'er, look.
زينير، انظر.
This is the man you once trusted and relied on.
هذا هو الرجل الذي كنت تثق به وتعتمد عليه في السابق.
Your Highness, His Majesty is busy.
صاحب السمو، جلالته مشغول.
So I dare not disturb him.
لذلك لا أجرؤ على إزعاجه.
If His Majesty knew you were seriously ill,
إذا كان جلالته يعلم أنك مريض مرضاً خطيراً،
he would...
كان سيفعل...
Eunuch Fu,
الخصي فو،
thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Prince Rui sent a physician.
أرسل الأمير روي طبيباً.
Sorry to trouble you for nothing.
أعتذر عن إزعاجك بلا داعٍ.
Also,
أيضًا،
stop reporting my affairs to His Majesty.
توقفوا عن إبلاغ جلالته بشؤوني.
- Your Highness... - You may withdraw.
- صاحب السمو... - يمكنك الانسحاب.
I'll take my leave.
سأغادر الآن.
Please take care, Your Highness.
يرجى توخي الحذر يا صاحب السمو.
(Is this Lu Zhen'er,)
(هل هذا لو زينير،)
(my once domineering consort?)
(زوجتي التي كانت متسلطة في السابق؟)
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I want to leave the palace.
أريد مغادرة القصر.
But I want Yindan with me.
لكنني أريد يندان معي.
Do you have a way?
هل لديك طريقة؟
Certainly.
بالتأكيد.
Zhen'er,
زينير،
wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكراً لك يا صاحب السمو.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
no more thanks from me.
لا مزيد من الشكر مني.
Good.
جيد.
Here.
هنا.
♪Spring comes late after the snow♪
يأتي الربيع متأخراً بعد الثلج.
♪Having endured sorrow and joy♪
بعد أن تحملنا الحزن والفرح
♪Wandering the streets, the story unfinished♪
أتجول في الشوارع، والقصة لم تكتمل.
♪Turning around, I lost you♪
عندما استدرت، فقدتُ أثرك.
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي.
♪Our reunion veiled by moonlight♪
لقاؤنا محجوب بضوء القمر؟
♪Grant me indifference or tenderness♪
أرجو أن تمنحني اللامبالاة أو الحنان.
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
???تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف؟؟؟
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح.
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
الشوق ينسج في شبكة.
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر.
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
ومع ذلك، أتوق إلى نظرتك.
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
الزمن، تاركاً وراءه الكثير من الماضي.
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
الخراب يتبع المجد
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا؟
♪Will I kiss your face♪
هل سأقبل وجهك؟
♪Never forgotten, hope you've been well♪
لن ننساك أبدًا، أتمنى أن تكون بخير.
♪Borrowing the first ray of spring light♪
استعارة أول شعاع من ضوء الربيع؟
♪Can it bring about for us?♪
هل يمكن أن يحقق لنا ذلك؟
♪One look back, lasting till the end of time♪
نظرة واحدة إلى الوراء، تدوم إلى نهاية الزمان.
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح.
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
الشوق ينسج في شبكة.
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر.
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
ومع ذلك، أتوق إلى نظرتك.
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
الزمن، تاركاً وراءه الكثير من الماضي.
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
الخراب يتبع المجد
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا؟
♪Will I kiss your face♪
هل سأقبل وجهك؟